我们的下一个原则是避免使用神奇的数字。
Our next principle is avoiding magic numbers.
那么什么是神奇数字？
So what's a magic number?
在计算机科学中只有两个数字
Well, there are really only two numbers in computer science
首先。
to begin with.
0和1。
0 and 1.
我们也可以允许2。
We could also allow 2.
但是所有其他的数字和常数
But all other numbers and constants in general
被称为魔法如果他们自己出现没有名字。
are called magic if they appear by themselves without names.
所以一年中的每一天都充满了这些神奇的数字。
So day of year is full of these magic numbers.
我们在这里看到2，在这里看到31，在这里看到3，
We see a 2 here, we see a 31 here, we see a 3 here,
59号。
59 there.
这些是魔法，因为代码无法解释它们的含义，
These are magic because the code doesn't explain what they mean,
他们代表什么，来自哪里。
what they represent, and where they came from.
修复幻数的一种方法是
One way to fix magic number is to make
更可读的代码是替换那些未命名的常量
code more readable is to replace those unnamed constants
使用命名常量。
with named constants.
所以这个数字是2，因为它实际上
So this number here, 2, because it actually
代表二月，
is supposed to represent February,
如果它真的
would be much clearer if it actually
是一个叫二月的常数。
was a constant named February.
这些数字代表了一个月的几天，
For these numbers that represent the days of the month,
实际上，最好将它们放入数组中。
it would actually better to put them into an array.
一个命名数组，比如月长，
A named array, like month's length,
然后你就可以索引这个月的数字。
that you can then index on the number of the month.
这些神奇的数字特别糟糕，因为它们
These magic numbers are particularly bad because they
由程序员手工计算
are computed by hand by the programmer
在没有任何解释的情况下
and just dropped into this code without any explanation of what
计算是产生它们的原因。
the computation was that produced them.
这几乎不是个好主意。
This is almost never a good idea.
不要用手工和硬计算常数
Don't compute constants by hand and hard
把它们编码成你的代码。
code them into your code.
首先，因为编程语言
First, because the programming language
会比你更擅长算术的，
is going to be much better at that arithmetic than you are,
所以你应该把算术放进去。
so you should just put the arithmetic in there.
但是第二，因为它会更清晰
But second, because it will be clearer
给你看完的维修人员
to the maintainer coming after you reading it
59是从哪里来的。
where that 59 came from.
实际上是一月份的总和
That it's actually the sum of the length of January
还有二月的长度。
and the length of February.
所以不要用魔法数字。
So don't use magic numbers.
用名字好多了。
It's much better to use names.